<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Anak Wannaphaschaiyong</title>
    <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Anak Wannaphaschaiyong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Story of Evolution and Widespread Adoption of The Internet</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/a-brief-story-of-evolution-and-widespread-adoption-of-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/a-brief-story-of-evolution-and-widespread-adoption-of-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Internetworking Architecture&amp;rdquo; (Leiner et al. 2009) was a fundamental design that enable machines and computers to communicate via internet regardless of underlying communication protocol.
TCP/IP were implemented in UNIX operating system triggers a widespread adoption of internet (Leiner et al. 2009). Dispersion of protocols began in research community. Recall that predecessor of internet project (it was named &amp;ldquo;internetworking&amp;rdquo; at the time) was funded with the goal to increase speed and efficiency of research collaborations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Html is a Bad Design.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/html-is-a-bad-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/html-is-a-bad-design/</guid>
      <description>Alan Kay famously critique World Wide Web (WWW) where HTML is originated. He publicly dislike HTML as followed
 Things like [HTML] happens when we let physicists play with computer.
 He stated that HTML is a bad markup language because people who build HTML thinks their way of representing web page is the only way. He mentioned a (older and) better alternative to HTML is to define protocol based on ordered region on a tape &amp;mdash; back when tapes were still popular means of storage in 1950&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>