<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Anak Wannaphaschaiyong</title>
    <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Anak Wannaphaschaiyong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>  Philosophy and Meta Physics of &#34;Notes Taking&#34;
  </title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/philosophy-and-meta-physics-of-notes-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/philosophy-and-meta-physics-of-notes-taking/</guid>
      <description>Note taking is a skill that everyone seems to think that they have &amp;ldquo;solved&amp;rdquo; it. Whatever that means. They are not interested in investing their time to improve their note taking skill.
No interest. No skill. No framework.
Regardless of my critique, I think they draw conclusion fairly. Why? around 6 out of 10 people are knowledge worker 1. A subset of those need to use note at all. A subset of those who use notes need to create reusable notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assess Your Level of Understanding</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/assess-your-level-of-understanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/assess-your-level-of-understanding/</guid>
      <description>Ask youself the following question.
 How do you know your understand something? How can you access much do you understand it? If you don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand it yet, is there a way you can make a snapshot of things that you don&amp;rsquo;t understand such that you can replace this snapshot whenever a better &amp;ldquo;version&amp;rdquo; available to you.  Why ability to assess your level of understanding it important? you asked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom and Power are two sides of the same coin.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/freedom-and-power-are-two-sides-of-the-same-coin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/freedom-and-power-are-two-sides-of-the-same-coin/</guid>
      <description>According to dictionary, freedom is defined as
 The power or right to act, speak, or think as one wants without hindrance or restraint.
 Power is defined as
 The capacity or ability to direct or influence the behavior of others or the course of events.
 That&amp;rsquo;s is power is defined by abilities to restrict others&amp;rsquo; freedom. Therefore, by definitions, an individual with more power has more freedom than others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incentives Of Owning Money.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/incentives-of-owning-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/incentives-of-owning-money/</guid>
      <description>Edit History  last edit on [2022-07-30 Sat]    Money is the most flexible medium of exchange. For more detail please refer to my blog named &amp;ldquo;Money Is A Type of Token.&amp;rdquo;
Motivation drive efforts. Effort is a seed of creation and innovation. It just happens that money provides universal motivation due to its utility which is measured by speed of conversion from itself to other assets. Money has fastest conversion rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justifying Existent Of Company.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/justifying-existent-of-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/justifying-existent-of-company/</guid>
      <description>TBD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money Is A Type Of Token.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/money-is-a-type-of-token/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/money-is-a-type-of-token/</guid>
      <description>Edit History  last edit on [2022-07-30 Sat] I can refine this blog more by consolidating the current content to my notes on roam research. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to do this at the time of writing.      In theory, there is no need for &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; of exchange. Any exchange can be anything as long as seller and buyer agree upon. Therefore, one can argue that there will always exist a sequence of exchanges of agreements that satisfy any pair of sellers and buyers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Original OOP is fundamentally different to Modern OOP.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/original-oop-is-fundamentally-different-to-modern-oop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/original-oop-is-fundamentally-different-to-modern-oop/</guid>
      <description>Modern OOP is misused and misunderstood. Modern OOP create an object to abstract over the object internal state. Originally, OOP is intended to be used to abstract objects over the most important processes that take place within environment in which objects exit. This is done by exposing interfaces that are capable of interacting with the outside world 1. In the other word, an object should be built to be resurgence, to protect itself from dynamic environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Society As A Function Of Attention.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/society-as-a-function-of-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/society-as-a-function-of-attention/</guid>
      <description>Incentive is an underlying mechanism that drive society at any scale including individual, group of individuals, and human population as a whole.
Incentive is an abstract concept. Physically, incentives are driven by money, refer to my blog titled &amp;ldquo;Incentives of Owning Money&amp;rdquo; for more detail. Another important concept is to accept that money is an indirect form of freedom and power, refer to my blog titled &amp;ldquo;Blog Freedom and Power are two sides of the same coin&amp;rdquo; for more detail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>