<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Anak Wannaphaschaiyong</title>
    <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Anak Wannaphaschaiyong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>  Philosophy and Meta Physics of &#34;Notes Taking&#34;
  </title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/philosophy-and-meta-physics-of-notes-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/philosophy-and-meta-physics-of-notes-taking/</guid>
      <description>Note taking is a skill that everyone seems to think that they have &amp;ldquo;solved&amp;rdquo; it. Whatever that means. They are not interested in investing their time to improve their note taking skill.
No interest. No skill. No framework.
Regardless of my critique, I think they draw conclusion fairly. Why? around 6 out of 10 people are knowledge worker 1. A subset of those need to use note at all. A subset of those who use notes need to create reusable notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>  Writing a &#34;Blog&#34;
  </title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/writing-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/writing-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>Last edited  [2022-06-23 Thu]    Note: This blog will mostly likely ever changes as I form my preference of what I think a good blog should be.
Blog. Piece. Article. Whatever you called it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I will redefine it here. For the rest of the blog, I will use the word blog.
I define blog as followed
 Blog is a collection of text with a goal&amp;rsquo;s guided narrative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note of X where X = AWS EC2 services.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/a-note-of-x-where-x-aws-ec2-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/a-note-of-x-where-x-aws-ec2-services/</guid>
      <description>An EC2 instance has 4 state of life cycle: running, stopped, and terminated. Furthermore, state transition (or action) of an EC2 instance is launch, rebooting, pending, shutting-down, and stopping, see &amp;lt;ec2_life_cycle&amp;gt;.
  Figure 1: EC2 instance life cycle
  Validating that you have correct setup This article assumes that you have setup AWS credentials in your terminal environment. You can check out one of my article named &amp;ldquo;Setup AWS credentials for your AWS account and create new user&amp;rdquo; to help you set things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note of X where X = AWS IAM services.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/a-note-of-x-where-x-aws-iam-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/a-note-of-x-where-x-aws-iam-services/</guid>
      <description>In AWS IAM, a policy is the smallest entity of permission. There are types of policies: resources-based policy, identity-based policy, and session-based policy.
  Figure 1: aws policies
  Policies can be attached to the following &amp;ldquo;identity&amp;rdquo;: user (1 account can have more than 1 users), role, and group (a group has many user) 1. user, role, and group are called identity. In AWS identity is called IAM identity and user, role, and group are called IAM user, IAM role, and IAM user group, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note On Straight&#39;s Recipe.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/a-note-on-straights-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/a-note-on-straights-recipe/</guid>
      <description>Straight&amp;rsquo;s recipe is similar but not identify to one used by MELPA. 1
A recipe describes which local repository to link the files from and how to clone that repository, if repo is not found locally. With this definition of recipe, one can think of recipe as a build step (recipe) of a package.
Ultimately, a package is defined is a collection of files required for package&amp;rsquo;s build. striaght.el views a package in this manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note On Straight.el&#39;s Transaction</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/a-note-on-straight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/a-note-on-straight/</guid>
      <description>This article is based on staright.el README which at the moment doesn&amp;rsquo;t have written document on how transaction works. So This is a work in progress until I either read straight.el codebase or summarize its documentation.
Conceptually, stright.el clones Git repo and them symlinking files into Emacs&amp;rsquo;s load path. A packages in straight.el is defined as recipe as a files which was symlinked together. I have an article on recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assess Your Level of Understanding</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/assess-your-level-of-understanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/assess-your-level-of-understanding/</guid>
      <description>Ask youself the following question.
 How do you know your understand something? How can you access much do you understand it? If you don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand it yet, is there a way you can make a snapshot of things that you don&amp;rsquo;t understand such that you can replace this snapshot whenever a better &amp;ldquo;version&amp;rdquo; available to you.  Why ability to assess your level of understanding it important? you asked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building fundamental in Emacs: How to customize key binding in vanilla Emacs?</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/building-fundamental-in-emacs-how-to-customize-key-binding-in-vanilla-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/building-fundamental-in-emacs-how-to-customize-key-binding-in-vanilla-emacs/</guid>
      <description>When I first get into Emacs, I was a vim user before, so I picked up Doom Emacs without experience with vanilla Emacs. Transition has been smooth so far, but because I never has experience with Vanilla Emacs before when I encounter a bug in Doom Emacs. I always have to first figure out if it is Doom Emacs problem or Emacs problems. Because of this, I put out a new blog series to help me build a stronger foundation of Vanilla Emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of straight.el to other Emacs package manager.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/comparison-of-straight.el-to-other-emacs-package-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/comparison-of-straight.el-to-other-emacs-package-manager/</guid>
      <description>This article is an opinion piece on Comparison to other package managers.
Emacs package manager are split into 2 categories: package.el wrapper or not package.el wrapper.
One idea that straight.el emphasizes a lot is that straight.el manages commits rather than managing a whole a package. Some PM only accept latest commit. Other only accepts repo on github etc. I call this design decision a &amp;ldquo;smallest unit of design implementation.&amp;rdquo;
Other unique takes on managing Emacs packages are Borg (assimilates packages as Git submodules into .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive review of snippets management tools in emacs. The best way to manage code snippets in emacs.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/comprehensive-review-of-snippets-management-tools-in-emacs.-the-best-way-to-manage-code-snippets-in-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/comprehensive-review-of-snippets-management-tools-in-emacs.-the-best-way-to-manage-code-snippets-in-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Personally, I think snippets is under untilize. Same as notes. The fact is people just don&amp;rsquo;t do neither snippets or notes.
I defined code snippet as followed
 A collection of either small/large code which may store in single/multiple files that you will revisit against in the future.
 Focusing on manging code snippets in emacs, few packages come to mind including: yassnipet, auto-yasnippet, yankpad, and code library.
In my workflow, to share code snippet with others, gists is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Logs: Auto-YASnippet (aka aya) dive deep.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/dev-logs-auto-yasnippet-aka-aya-dive-deep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/dev-logs-auto-yasnippet-aka-aya-dive-deep/</guid>
      <description>Dev logs is new blog series which dive deep into implementation level. The goal is to understand how things works. I figure this should be an interesting series because I always wanted to know how these program works underneath. Instead of explaining the whole code base, I will only focus on the &amp;ldquo;magical&amp;rdquo; part that sparked my interest the most.
Todays I present to you aya.
I started of the series with aya because, I think, it is a small package with the right portion of magic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic inside blockchain: How does supply-demand mechanism works in blockchain?</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/economic-inside-blockchain-how-does-supply-demand-mechanism-works-in-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/economic-inside-blockchain-how-does-supply-demand-mechanism-works-in-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>Gas and Denominations of coins   Figure 1: Denominations of Ethers
  In this section, we will focus on denominations of Ethers. The goal is to provide more concrete example into denomination of a coin.
If you are familiar with Etherem, we have heard Wei and GWei. These are not the only two denominators of Ethers. List of all denominators of Ether is shown in Fig. which is from Etherem yellow paper (aka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Package Explained: How to customize key binding in evil modes?</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/emacs-package-explained-how-to-customize-key-binding-in-evil-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/emacs-package-explained-how-to-customize-key-binding-in-evil-modes/</guid>
      <description>This is my summary of a more thoroughly explained evil guide, see here.
Keymap Precendence in vanilla emacs  overriding-terminal-local-map for terminal-specific key bind overriding-local-map keymap char property at point keymaps for the current character. Yasnippet keymaps are in this category. emulation-mode-map-alists. Apparently, its more multi-mode keymap management. I am not sure what this means, but if i have to guess it is used in modes that have its known key precedence or other complexity that its key binding system brings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable x11 display in WSL2</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/enable-x11-display-in-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/enable-x11-display-in-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>Resources are provided in my roam research note.
I successfully connect x-apps via x11 protocol by first installing and launching xming server. Xming application provides x11-server. Then, I need to tell the wsl2 &amp;ldquo;address and port of X11 server to connect wsl2 application to&amp;rdquo; (my note on x11 can be seen here) X11 server is enlisted as WSL2 entrusted DNS which located in resolve.conf. (my note on resolve.conf can be seen here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Asset Transaction</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/evolution-of-asset-transaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/evolution-of-asset-transaction/</guid>
      <description>Hello, guys
This essay is my interpretation of a discussion on &amp;ldquo;NFTing the World for the General Good&amp;rdquo; episode on Real Vision TV. The information in the essay are adapted to fit rational narrative that I have in my brain.
This is the beginning of the essay.
The four phases are categorized into the following
 transaction an physical assets transaction of electron transaction of information transaction of digital assets  Each phase increase efficiency of transactions which depends on three factors: object, process, and rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedom and Power are two sides of the same coin.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/freedom-and-power-are-two-sides-of-the-same-coin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/freedom-and-power-are-two-sides-of-the-same-coin/</guid>
      <description>According to dictionary, freedom is defined as
 The power or right to act, speak, or think as one wants without hindrance or restraint.
 Power is defined as
 The capacity or ability to direct or influence the behavior of others or the course of events.
 That&amp;rsquo;s is power is defined by abilities to restrict others&amp;rsquo; freedom. Therefore, by definitions, an individual with more power has more freedom than others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting source code of distributed binary package in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/getting-source-code-of-distributed-binary-package-in-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/getting-source-code-of-distributed-binary-package-in-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>This stack exchange post state the following.
Debian and RPM packages don&amp;#39;t contain source code, only the compiled result. However, you can fetch the source packages - SRPMS, or the Debian description, patch, and original tarball. That&amp;rsquo;s it. You can only download file that are provided in url where target deb file is located. Which files will be provided? Only package maintainers can determine that. Therefore, there could be a scenario where no source codes are available for download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Guarantee Serialization with Two-Phase Locking (2PL) with Example</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-guarantee-serialization-with-two-phase-locking-2pl-with-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-guarantee-serialization-with-two-phase-locking-2pl-with-example/</guid>
      <description>This is a summary on Chapter 21.1 Two-Phase Locking Techniques for Concurrency Control from Fundamental of Database system by Pearson 2015.
The goal of this blog is to give a concrete example on how 2PL&amp;rsquo;s schedule is guaranteed to be serializable.
  Figure 1: Figure 21.3
    Figure 2: Figure 21.4
  Figure &amp;lt;Figure_21.3&amp;gt; and figure &amp;lt;Figure_21.4&amp;gt; uses the same set of locks which is provided in Shared/Exclusive locks including read_lock, write_lock and unlock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to parse text with awk?</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-parse-text-with-awk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-parse-text-with-awk/</guid>
      <description>ref  https://stackoverflow.com/questions/6284560/how-to-split-a-variable-by-a-special-character/6284596    Awk Syntax awk &amp;#39;(PATTERN1){...print something..} (PATTERN2){..print something..}&amp;#39; awk &amp;#39;PATTERN1{...print something..} PATTERN2{..print something..}&amp;#39; for each line, if PATTERNN is matched, command in {} will be executed.
syntax `awk &amp;lsquo;NR==1{print}&amp;rsquo; [FILE]` `awk &amp;lsquo;NR==1&amp;rsquo; [FILE]` note for line 1, print whole line `awk &amp;lsquo;NR==1{}&amp;rsquo; [FILE]` note for line 1, {} = don&amp;rsquo;t do anything `awk &amp;lsquo;NR==1{print} {print}&amp;rsquo; [FILE]` note {} without condition is the same as condition always set to True.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to publish blog on Jekyll with example.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-publish-blog-on-jekyll-with-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-publish-blog-on-jekyll-with-example/</guid>
      <description>You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run `jekyll serve`, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.
Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:
`YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP`
Where `YEAR` is a four-digit number, `MONTH` and `DAY` are both two-digit numbers, and `MARKUP` is the file extension representing the format used in the file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to set local variable for a specific mode?</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-set-local-variable-for-a-specific-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-set-local-variable-for-a-specific-mode/</guid>
      <description>This type of tutorial/question is best to present with an example. Given that I want to set compile-command variable for LaTex mode which applies to all buffer of this mode.
(defun set-compile-command-default-in-LaTeX-mode () (set (make-local-variable &amp;#39;compile-command) ;; create local variable specific to a current buffer (format &amp;#34;&amp;#34; (buffer-file-name)))) (add-hook &amp;#39;LaTeX-mode-hook &amp;#39;set-compile-command-default-in-LaTeX-mode) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use auto yasnippet (aka aya) in your workflow?</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-use-auto-yasnippet-aka-aya-in-your-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-use-auto-yasnippet-aka-aya-in-your-workflow/</guid>
      <description>All of the content I presented below can be found at Auto-YASnippet Github repo.
Auto-Yasnippet (aka aya) provides the following interactive commands: aya-create, aya-expand, aya-persiste-snippet, and aya-open-line:
I don&amp;rsquo;t quite understand aya-open-line yet, so I will not be explaining it here.
This snippet package support ad-hoc style of editing workflow where you can create useful snippet to be reused as you editing.
Without aya, one would have do the following</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of X where X = Emac&#39;s auth-source.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/implementation-of-x-where-x-emacs-auth-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/implementation-of-x-where-x-emacs-auth-source/</guid>
      <description>As an example, I will use api.github.com as a API endpoint.
If I use ~/.authinfo.gpg as an auth-sources file. (variable name is auth-sources), I need to add the following to the file where I need to sub value into user-username and user-password.
machine api.github.com login user-name password user-password auth-source-search is a function that retrieve password from your specify auth-sources file. You can use it as followed. This will output list of property where :secret key has your password as its value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incentives Of Owning Money.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/incentives-of-owning-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/incentives-of-owning-money/</guid>
      <description>Edit History  last edit on [2022-07-30 Sat]    Money is the most flexible medium of exchange. For more detail please refer to my blog named &amp;ldquo;Money Is A Type of Token.&amp;rdquo;
Motivation drive efforts. Effort is a seed of creation and innovation. It just happens that money provides universal motivation due to its utility which is measured by speed of conversion from itself to other assets. Money has fastest conversion rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justifying Existent Of Company.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/justifying-existent-of-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/justifying-existent-of-company/</guid>
      <description>TBD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keybinding In Doom Emacs</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/keybinding-in-doom-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/keybinding-in-doom-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Doom Emacs has its own keybinding system. A more accurate explaination is
 Doom Emacs keybinding system is a wrapper over evil mode such that it is smoothly compatible with Emacs.
 If you use Evil mode without Emacs configuration framework such as Spacemacs or Doom Emacs, it is frustrating to know if your keybinding is setup properly and whether it will always work as expected in any circumstances. A common point of failure is when your keybinding is overwritten by some packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money Is A Type Of Token.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/money-is-a-type-of-token/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/money-is-a-type-of-token/</guid>
      <description>Edit History  last edit on [2022-07-30 Sat] I can refine this blog more by consolidating the current content to my notes on roam research. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to do this at the time of writing.      In theory, there is no need for &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; of exchange. Any exchange can be anything as long as seller and buyer agree upon. Therefore, one can argue that there will always exist a sequence of exchanges of agreements that satisfy any pair of sellers and buyers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Efficient Workflow To &#34;Lookup&#34; Documentations On Programming Language.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/most-efficient-workflow-to-lookup-documentations-on-programming-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/most-efficient-workflow-to-lookup-documentations-on-programming-language/</guid>
      <description>The normal workflow of lookup documentation would be to search google, stack-overflow, etc. Alternatively, if you are using IDE, IDE will lookup documentation for you, for example goto-definition etc. Very convenience. What else do you need?
Although, searching online directly is not the best approach, it is everyone last line of defense. On the other hands, IDE is as good as it gets. However, the problem with IDE is that it is context specific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Citation Management Workflow.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/my-citation-management-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/my-citation-management-workflow/</guid>
      <description>there are three categories of note taking process
 organize files. write notes on a file. search files and notes (aka completion in emacs) organize notes reference to file.  First two are easy to achieve. Put notes and pdf files in folders does the job. The third condition is arguably not difficult neither. One can search for a file given a file directory quickly which can be done with any of the completion packages (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note Taking Pipeline Framework.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/note-taking-pipeline-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/note-taking-pipeline-framework/</guid>
      <description>I propose &amp;ldquo;Note Taking Pipeline Framework&amp;rdquo; as my take on how I implement my &amp;ldquo;second brain.&amp;rdquo; I would argue with a high degree of certainty that this framework is the best in the world without degree of exaggeration.
I think of note taking as a type of data storage with a property that satisfy my note taking philosophy. I wrote about philosophy of note taking in my blog titled &amp;ldquo;Philosophy and Meta Physics of &amp;lsquo;Notes Taking&amp;rsquo;&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Docker Container With Dockerfile.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/running-docker-container-with-dockerfile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/running-docker-container-with-dockerfile/</guid>
      <description>As an example, the goal is to run container that will download things hosted on the web and run some command DURING a docker launches (using ENTRYPOINT to run the command).
FROMubuntuRUN apt-get updateRUN apt-get install -y wgetRUN apt-get install -y unzipRUN apt-get install -y ffmpegRUN wget https://www.cse.fau.edu/~hari/sequences/vid-clips.zipRUN unzip vid-clips.zipENTRYPOINT [&amp;#34;ffmpeg&amp;#34; -i&amp;#34; clip-crf20.mp4&amp;#34; -c:v&amp;#34; libx264&amp;#34; -crf&amp;#34; 36&amp;#34; -c:a&amp;#34; copy&amp;#34; clip-out.mp4&amp;#34;]If you are not root user when you run apt-get install [package], you must confirm yes or no to installation which requires user input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup AWS credentials for your AWS account and create new user.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/setup-aws-credentials-for-your-aws-account-and-create-new-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/setup-aws-credentials-for-your-aws-account-and-create-new-user/</guid>
      <description>AWS credentials and configuration to your AWS account. AWS configuration file and credential file can be found at ~/.aws/config and ~/.aws/credentials.
Once that done, you can use the following to get your account information.
aws sts get-caller-identity It will not show secret key aws_access_key_id and aws_secret_access_key which you have set. It will only show information of your account including: UserId, AccountId, Arn.
AWS users Note that 1 account has 1 root and can have many IAM user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Society As A Function Of Attention.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/society-as-a-function-of-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/society-as-a-function-of-attention/</guid>
      <description>Incentive is an underlying mechanism that drive society at any scale including individual, group of individuals, and human population as a whole.
Incentive is an abstract concept. Physically, incentives are driven by money, refer to my blog titled &amp;ldquo;Incentives of Owning Money&amp;rdquo; for more detail. Another important concept is to accept that money is an indirect form of freedom and power, refer to my blog titled &amp;ldquo;Blog Freedom and Power are two sides of the same coin&amp;rdquo; for more detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using terminals in Doom Emacs.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/using-terminals-in-doom-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/using-terminals-in-doom-emacs/</guid>
      <description>To open multiple terminal, a neat trick is to rename file buffer that terminal is opened 1.
To open file from terminal, one can just M-x find-file in the terminal buffer.
  stackoverflow: More than one emacs terminal &amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Terraform to set up ec2 instances for data science projects.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/using-terraform-to-set-up-ec2-instances-for-data-science-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/using-terraform-to-set-up-ec2-instances-for-data-science-projects/</guid>
      <description>Take Away  you will learn how to automate ec2 setup using terraform that is suited for data science project.  Tools  EC2 Terraform  Requirements Knowledge Requirements  understand basic of how to create terraform project understand basic of how to set up ec2 instances  System Requirements   WSL/Ubuntu
 I have only tested this in WSL    install all dependencies of cuda
 for list of software requirements, see  https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is X Where X Is Docker&#39;s Image?</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/what-is-x-where-x-is-dockers-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/what-is-x-where-x-is-dockers-image/</guid>
      <description>Edit log  [2022-07-25 Mon]    I was following &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s A Docker Image Anyway?&amp;quot; 1, but found that its content is no longer true, there are new changes to metadata of docker image, so I write this blog to reflect the changes that I observed at the time of writing.
docker -v          Docker version 20.10.17 build 100c701    I write the following Dockerfile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the f*** is wiki.c2.com? and its potential for mainstream adoption.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/what-the-f-is-wiki.c2.com-and-its-potential-for-mainstream-adoption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/what-the-f-is-wiki.c2.com-and-its-potential-for-mainstream-adoption/</guid>
      <description>last edit  [2022-06-26 Sun]    One of my life long projects is to build an index protocol using tokenomics for thought sharing. For now, on [2022-06-26 Sun], I call it &amp;ldquo;The Forest.&amp;rdquo;
On [2022-06-26 Sun], I stumbled upon wiki.c2.com. I was reading about it for a couple hours, and wiki.c2.com seems to share lots of philosophy that The Forest holds. Two hours in, however, I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to get a grip of some very basic stuff like how to read it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X Implementation Where X = Doom Emacs&#39;s &#43;lookup/ Command.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/x-implementation-where-x-doom-emacss-&#43;lookup-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/x-implementation-where-x-doom-emacss-&#43;lookup-command/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to figure out +lookup/definition that open in other window. In one of the issue, Henrik 1 mention that some lookup backend (As an example, xref is a built in backend for lookup) are asynchronous and there is no standardized mechanism to talk to them to see whether the command runs successfully 2.
lets call this new command +lookup/definition-other-window Current possible solutions are
 ignore validation step to make sure that the command runs succesfully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X implementation where X = executing org babel block in Doom Emacs.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/x-implementation-where-x-executing-org-babel-block-in-doom-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/x-implementation-where-x-executing-org-babel-block-in-doom-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Editing History  [2022-07-06 Wed] Last edit is on [2022-07-07 Thu]    This article investigates what is executed when one presses enter to execute org babel source block in Doom Emacs.
Pressing enter in org-babel block will execute +org/dwim-at-point, see code below for reference. First, it checks if point is on a button. Then, it proceeds to assign evaluated output of org-element-context and org-element-type.
(+org/dwim-at-point *optional ARG) .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>