<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aya on Anak Wannaphaschaiyong</title>
    <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/tags/aya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aya on Anak Wannaphaschaiyong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/tags/aya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev Logs: Auto-YASnippet (aka aya) dive deep.</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/dev-logs-auto-yasnippet-aka-aya-dive-deep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/dev-logs-auto-yasnippet-aka-aya-dive-deep/</guid>
      <description>Dev logs is new blog series which dive deep into implementation level. The goal is to understand how things works. I figure this should be an interesting series because I always wanted to know how these program works underneath. Instead of explaining the whole code base, I will only focus on the &amp;ldquo;magical&amp;rdquo; part that sparked my interest the most.
Todays I present to you aya.
I started of the series with aya because, I think, it is a small package with the right portion of magic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use auto yasnippet (aka aya) in your workflow?</title>
      <link>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-use-auto-yasnippet-aka-aya-in-your-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://awannaphasch2016.github.io/posts/how-to-use-auto-yasnippet-aka-aya-in-your-workflow/</guid>
      <description>All of the content I presented below can be found at Auto-YASnippet Github repo.
Auto-Yasnippet (aka aya) provides the following interactive commands: aya-create, aya-expand, aya-persiste-snippet, and aya-open-line:
I don&amp;rsquo;t quite understand aya-open-line yet, so I will not be explaining it here.
This snippet package support ad-hoc style of editing workflow where you can create useful snippet to be reused as you editing.
Without aya, one would have do the following</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>